RG 069:143, Willis H. Birge Financial Papers
Connecticut State Library
Willis H. Birge financial papers
1799-1938
Connecticut State Library
Birge, Willis H.
.5 cubic feet
Willis H. Birge was a farmer and a tobacco grower in Windsor Locks, Conn.
RG069_143
2008-033
Biographical Note
Willis Henry Birge was born on January 1, 1859 in Windsor Locks, Connecticut, to Henry and Eliza H. (Viets) Birge. Both Willis' father Henry (1814-1899) and his grandfather David Birge (1770-1847) were wagon makers. On February 11, 1880, Birge married Hattie Montgomery Sargent, also of Windsor Locks. Birge made a living as a farmer and tobacco grower. He died in Plainville, Connecticut on April 29, 1957, aged 98 years.
Scope and Content
Included are various financial papers kept by Willis H. Birge: an account book, 1880-1938; an account book for a sawmill, 1880-1885; two volumes of cash payments, 1880-1902; a volume of cash received, 1879-1902; and various bills and receipts, 1885-1914. There are two additional account books. One belonged to Henry Birge, 1850-1859, 1876. The other, with entries dating 1799-1802, 1843-1847, is unidentified although the later entries were added by Henry. There are also two cabinet card photographs dated 1859. One is of Henry Birge. The other is of his wife Eliza holding the infant Willis H. Birge.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Persons:
Birge, Willis H.; Birge, Henry
Places:
Windsor Locks (Conn.)
Occupations:
Farmers; Wheelwrights
Document Types:
Account books; Cashbooks; Photographs; Receipts (financial records)
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
This collection was donated to the Connecticut State Library by Annabelle Gerish on January 15, 2008. Gerish's husband, Fred W. Gerish, was the grandson of Willis H. Birge.
Container List
- Financial Papers, 1799-1938
  - Account book, unidentified, 1799-1802, 1843-1847 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    A small number of later entries, 1843-1847, were made by Henry Birge.
  - Henry Birge account book, 1850-1859, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Account book, 1880-1938; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Account book for sawmill, 1880-1885; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cash payment books, 1880-1902; 2 volumes (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cash recieved book, 1879-1902; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bills and receipts, 1885-1914 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Insurance policies and receipts, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1895-1914, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cabinet card photographs (Box 1)
    - Henry Birge, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Eliza Ann (Viets) Birge with Willis Henry Birge, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 9)